Installing Windows Calculator
This is a custom made installation setup for the app built inside Visual Studio with InstallShield.
Developed in C# programming language.
Designed using Windows Forms for the user interface.
In action performing standard calculations. Some of the functions
include:
- Delete last entry and perform different calculation;
- Users can change the mathematical operator at any time;
- Some of the processes happening behind the scenes are: User Input Validation, Error Handling for smooth application performance.
- It filters garbage data and produces error free outputs to the user - for example if an operator is pressed more than once.
- It works with negative values and percentages.
User Accessibility and Usability is implemented via keyboard navigation, Mnemonics, Hot Keys, Tool Tips and change of System Colour Scheme.
For example visually impaired people can use screen reader software to navigate around with the TAB button.
Pressing ALT on your keyboard activates Mnemonics that underlines frequentlly used buttons and menus.
In this case last entry is deleted by pressing 'D' button and with 'C' you can clear all of the entries.
Like so users can access the menu by pressing 'M'
and by selecting the hot key 'Ctrl + C' you can exit the app.
Yet other helpful feature is the High Contrast function that
performs validation over the Windows OS system colour scheme.
In this mode other users can still access all of the functions within the app.
Tool Tips are very good way to tell and inform users how to use
the application and make their choice.
Thank you for watching.